<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shreyas Mayya</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shreyas Mayya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 19:33:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Right Now - 7/1/2020</title>
      <link>/2020/07/life-right-now-7/1/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 19:33:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/life-right-now-7/1/2020/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t have much to ruminate upon today, so instead here&#39;s a look at my life right now:
  Summer CS has been going relatively well&amp;ndash;since I&#39;ve done most of the labs beforehand, I just make sure that they work and put all the classes into one file before going and doing something else.
  I finished writing up part one of this year&#39;s edition of my annual TJMC show piano arrangement last night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emails</title>
      <link>/2020/06/emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 13:12:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/emails/</guid>
      <description>I have to send out a bunch of emails. The recipients: potential sponsors for HackTJ 7.5, a virtual version of the school&#39;s annual hackathon that&#39;s set to take place in November. I know whom I&#39;m supposed to contact, and more or less what to talk about in my messages. I even double-checked everything the other day to make sure I wasn&#39;t mistaken. So why don&#39;t I want to do it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mother Tongue</title>
      <link>/2020/06/mother-tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 12:14:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/mother-tongue/</guid>
      <description>At TJ, a large portion of the student body comes from households where English isn&#39;t the only language spoken. Their families might converse in Tamil or Telugu, Chinese or Korean1&amp;ndash;and as a result, most of the kids from those backgrounds are fluent in their families&#39; native tongues. It&#39;s impressive&amp;hellip; and a bit disheartening, honestly. You see, I&#39;m from one of those households, but I&#39;ve always struggled to speak the language of my family, and it&#39;s caused me some problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lukewarm</title>
      <link>/2020/06/lukewarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 13:35:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/lukewarm/</guid>
      <description>Nothing hurts quite like a lukewarm response.
You&#39;ve probably seen or felt it before: telling someone about a subject you really enjoy only to have them respond with a dismissive &amp;quot;Yeah, that&#39;s cool&amp;quot;, or a stand-up comedian delivering their best joke to a crowd and receiving almost no laughs in return. It&#39;s pretty awful. Boredom (or at least the perception of it) is anathema to the entertainer&amp;ndash;a sign that the audience doesn&#39;t care about what they have to say, that they failed at the most important element of what they&#39;re supposed to be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containers</title>
      <link>/2020/06/containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 16:42:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/containers/</guid>
      <description>I just finished containerizing this site1, and it had me thinking.
In the systems administration world, a container is a small virtual environment that can be used to run a program or service. These little things are made using templates called images. There are a few advantages to this model:
 Containers are pretty easy to create. They&#39;re also easy and clean to delete. They&#39;re more isolated than just running on bare metal, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Week</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:31:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-last-week/</guid>
      <description>Today, June 26, marks 15 weeks since my first day in quarantine. For reference, that&#39;s a long time.1 Since I don&#39;t want to review Java graphics concepts (¿Qué es un búfer?), I figured I would look back on the events leading up to the closing of in-person school.2
March 6, 2020  Virginia Science Olympiad sent out an email saying that they were monitoring the situation.  March 7, 2020  Southern California Science Olympiad decided to cancel their state tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distro Updates</title>
      <link>/2020/06/distro-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:09:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/distro-updates/</guid>
      <description>As if it wasn&#39;t already abundantly clear that I have too much time on my hands, I did some distrohopping today.
What is distrohopping? For the uninitiated, distrohopping is the practice of jumping between Linux distributions (or &amp;quot;distros&amp;quot;) because&amp;hellip; well, because you can, I suppose. (I want to write a longer post about distrohopping, so keep an eye out for that!)
Well, what did you switch to? Without further ado:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Humorist</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-humorist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 09:50:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-humorist/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been noticing something over the last few weeks&amp;ndash;I like to crack jokes. A lot. Here are just a few examples from recent text conversations: 1
 When I failed to properly read information about the school district opening back up for the next school year: &amp;quot;Hey, they only mentioned science and technology in our school&#39;s name, not literacy.&amp;quot; 2 After reading a post by the principal about how we were more than our our GPAs: &amp;quot;Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>/2020/06/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 10:15:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/hello/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I&#39;ll admit I&#39;m not used to writing about my life, so instead of a recollection of some distant memory I&#39;ll just make up a few questions and answer them.
Why did you make a blog? I&#39;d been considering creating a blog for some time now. It seemed like a good way of sharing my thoughts while gaining the catharsis that comes with expressing myself. However, I&#39;m also a painfully reserved person, and my fear of opening up kept me from making this site earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>