<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shreyas Mayya</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shreyas Mayya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 12:31:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aristocrat Encode with libcodebusters</title>
      <link>/2020/09/aristocrat-encode-with-libcodebusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 12:31:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/aristocrat-encode-with-libcodebusters/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first entry in my libcodebusters series! In these, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the various methods in my libcodebusters code and how they work.
libcodebusters is basically a bunch of methods that allow you to encode and decode text with a variety of ciphers. I&amp;rsquo;ve made Java and Python versions of the code.
The first method I&amp;rsquo;ll be explaining is that for Aristocrat encoding. The Aristocrat is a very well-known monoalphabetic substitution cipher with a few important characteristics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do the Dreams Mean?</title>
      <link>/2020/08/what-do-the-dreams-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:16:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/what-do-the-dreams-mean/</guid>
      <description>I opened my eyes to darkness. It was some ungodly hour on Saturday morning, and I was struggling to make sense of a scene I just saw. I remembered the details really well,1 but how did everything happen if I had just been sleeping? It took a couple seconds before the realization hit me that I had been dreaming.2
Later that day, I recounted this occurrence to a friend, and he wondered if there was something more to the whole thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James and the Looming Specter of Suicide</title>
      <link>/2020/07/james-and-the-looming-specter-of-suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 17:01:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/james-and-the-looming-specter-of-suicide/</guid>
      <description>(DISCLAIMER: In case it wasn&#39;t obvious enough, this will be a pretty somber post. You&#39;ve been warned.)
Meet James. James is a rising senior at TJ. James likes to run and has been a part of TJ&#39;s cross-country and track teams. He&#39;s also passionate about photography and videography.
Oh, sorry. Did I write &amp;quot;is&amp;quot;? Because I meant to write &amp;quot;was&amp;quot;. Sadly, today marks one week since James committed suicide.
James wasn&#39;t the first TJ student to unexpectedly pass away&amp;ndash;he wasn&#39;t even the first in his own graduating class&amp;ndash;but his death is the latest item added to a laundry list of mental health concerns at the school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 12, 1784</title>
      <link>/2020/07/may-12-1784/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 19:30:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/may-12-1784/</guid>
      <description>To my fellow Americans: happy Independence Day! As we all know, July 4th, 1776 marked the birth of the United States with the signing of the Declaration of Independence. But here&#39;s my hot take for the day&amp;ndash;we&#39;re celebrating the wrong date. (And no, John Adams nerds, I don&#39;t mean we should be celebrating July 2nd instead.) In my view, the real date of America&#39;s founding is a few years later, on May 12, 1784.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sped Up</title>
      <link>/2020/07/sped-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 20:36:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/sped-up/</guid>
      <description>I have an interesting quirk when it comes to classical music: I like to speed my music up. It&#39;s not drastic&amp;ndash;usually anywhere from 5 to 15%, depending on the piece&amp;ndash;but it is noticeable. I have friends who do similar things with TV programs or movies they might be watching, and it got me thinking about our attention spans. What&#39;s the use of consuming sped-up content, and why do we prefer it to normal speed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mother Tongue</title>
      <link>/2020/06/mother-tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 12:14:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/mother-tongue/</guid>
      <description>At TJ, a large portion of the student body comes from households where English isn&#39;t the only language spoken. Their families might converse in Tamil or Telugu, Chinese or Korean1&amp;ndash;and as a result, most of the kids from those backgrounds are fluent in their families&#39; native tongues. It&#39;s impressive&amp;hellip; and a bit disheartening, honestly. You see, I&#39;m from one of those households, but I&#39;ve always struggled to speak the language of my family, and it&#39;s caused me some problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containers</title>
      <link>/2020/06/containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 16:42:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/containers/</guid>
      <description>I just finished containerizing this site1, and it had me thinking.
In the systems administration world, a container is a small virtual environment that can be used to run a program or service. These little things are made using templates called images. There are a few advantages to this model:
 Containers are pretty easy to create. They&#39;re also easy and clean to delete. They&#39;re more isolated than just running on bare metal, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Week</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:31:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-last-week/</guid>
      <description>Today, June 26, marks 15 weeks since my first day in quarantine. For reference, that&#39;s a long time.1 Since I don&#39;t want to review Java graphics concepts (¿Qué es un búfer?), I figured I would look back on the events leading up to the closing of in-person school.2
March 6, 2020  Virginia Science Olympiad sent out an email saying that they were monitoring the situation.  March 7, 2020  Southern California Science Olympiad decided to cancel their state tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Humorist</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-humorist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 09:50:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-humorist/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been noticing something over the last few weeks&amp;ndash;I like to crack jokes. A lot. Here are just a few examples from recent text conversations: 1
 When I failed to properly read information about the school district opening back up for the next school year: &amp;quot;Hey, they only mentioned science and technology in our school&#39;s name, not literacy.&amp;quot; 2 After reading a post by the principal about how we were more than our our GPAs: &amp;quot;Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>/2020/06/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 10:15:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/hello/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I&#39;ll admit I&#39;m not used to writing about my life, so instead of a recollection of some distant memory I&#39;ll just make up a few questions and answer them.
Why did you make a blog? I&#39;d been considering creating a blog for some time now. It seemed like a good way of sharing my thoughts while gaining the catharsis that comes with expressing myself. However, I&#39;m also a painfully reserved person, and my fear of opening up kept me from making this site earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
