<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why? on Shreyas Mayya</title>
    <link>/categories/why/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Why? on Shreyas Mayya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 15:44:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/why/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghosts</title>
      <link>/2020/07/ghosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 15:44:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/ghosts/</guid>
      <description>As soon as you saw the title of this post, you probably thought this would be about one of two things:
 Actual ghosts, like Casper Ghosting  The second is correct. Congratulations!
I&#39;ve noticed a fair bit of &amp;quot;leaving on delivered&amp;quot; going on lately, and I&#39;ve been both the recipient and the perpetrator. (In the latter scenario, it was because I would keep getting involved with something and forgetting to check my messages, though my laziness did also start to protest my attempts to help others with their CS work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sped Up</title>
      <link>/2020/07/sped-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 20:36:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/sped-up/</guid>
      <description>I have an interesting quirk when it comes to classical music: I like to speed my music up. It&#39;s not drastic&amp;ndash;usually anywhere from 5 to 15%, depending on the piece&amp;ndash;but it is noticeable. I have friends who do similar things with TV programs or movies they might be watching, and it got me thinking about our attention spans. What&#39;s the use of consuming sped-up content, and why do we prefer it to normal speed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lukewarm</title>
      <link>/2020/06/lukewarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 13:35:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/lukewarm/</guid>
      <description>Nothing hurts quite like a lukewarm response.
You&#39;ve probably seen or felt it before: telling someone about a subject you really enjoy only to have them respond with a dismissive &amp;quot;Yeah, that&#39;s cool&amp;quot;, or a stand-up comedian delivering their best joke to a crowd and receiving almost no laughs in return. It&#39;s pretty awful. Boredom (or at least the perception of it) is anathema to the entertainer&amp;ndash;a sign that the audience doesn&#39;t care about what they have to say, that they failed at the most important element of what they&#39;re supposed to be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Humorist</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-humorist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 09:50:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-humorist/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been noticing something over the last few weeks&amp;ndash;I like to crack jokes. A lot. Here are just a few examples from recent text conversations: 1
 When I failed to properly read information about the school district opening back up for the next school year: &amp;quot;Hey, they only mentioned science and technology in our school&#39;s name, not literacy.&amp;quot; 2 After reading a post by the principal about how we were more than our our GPAs: &amp;quot;Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>