<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Shreyas Mayya</title>
    <link>/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Shreyas Mayya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:16:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do the Dreams Mean?</title>
      <link>/2020/08/what-do-the-dreams-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:16:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/what-do-the-dreams-mean/</guid>
      <description>I opened my eyes to darkness. It was some ungodly hour on Saturday morning, and I was struggling to make sense of a scene I just saw. I remembered the details really well,1 but how did everything happen if I had just been sleeping? It took a couple seconds before the realization hit me that I had been dreaming.2
Later that day, I recounted this occurrence to a friend, and he wondered if there was something more to the whole thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mother Tongue</title>
      <link>/2020/06/mother-tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 12:14:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/mother-tongue/</guid>
      <description>At TJ, a large portion of the student body comes from households where English isn&#39;t the only language spoken. Their families might converse in Tamil or Telugu, Chinese or Korean1&amp;ndash;and as a result, most of the kids from those backgrounds are fluent in their families&#39; native tongues. It&#39;s impressive&amp;hellip; and a bit disheartening, honestly. You see, I&#39;m from one of those households, but I&#39;ve always struggled to speak the language of my family, and it&#39;s caused me some problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containers</title>
      <link>/2020/06/containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 16:42:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/containers/</guid>
      <description>I just finished containerizing this site1, and it had me thinking.
In the systems administration world, a container is a small virtual environment that can be used to run a program or service. These little things are made using templates called images. There are a few advantages to this model:
 Containers are pretty easy to create. They&#39;re also easy and clean to delete. They&#39;re more isolated than just running on bare metal, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Week</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-last-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:31:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-last-week/</guid>
      <description>Today, June 26, marks 15 weeks since my first day in quarantine. For reference, that&#39;s a long time.1 Since I don&#39;t want to review Java graphics concepts (¿Qué es un búfer?), I figured I would look back on the events leading up to the closing of in-person school.2
March 6, 2020  Virginia Science Olympiad sent out an email saying that they were monitoring the situation.  March 7, 2020  Southern California Science Olympiad decided to cancel their state tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Humorist</title>
      <link>/2020/06/the-humorist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 09:50:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/the-humorist/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been noticing something over the last few weeks&amp;ndash;I like to crack jokes. A lot. Here are just a few examples from recent text conversations: 1
 When I failed to properly read information about the school district opening back up for the next school year: &amp;quot;Hey, they only mentioned science and technology in our school&#39;s name, not literacy.&amp;quot; 2 After reading a post by the principal about how we were more than our our GPAs: &amp;quot;Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>